Joe Richards

Senior Software Engineer | Manila, 1011 | joerichards20511@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly versatile full-stack software engineer with 8+ years of professional web development experience. Helped many companies take an idea and turn it into a product that serves thousands to millions of users. Built the software that powers Tesla's service centers for scheduling from scratch and worked at big tech companies, such as Atlassian, Snapchat and Starbucks. Known for building fast and exceptionally well, and could work on either end of the stack.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

2023 - 2024

- Implemented several features across Atlassian core products.
- Led and oversaw the high-level architecture of multiple initiatives.
- Implemented various performance-related initiatives to improve customer experience.

Software Engineer 2022 – 2023

Pidwin

- Built, managed, owned, and scaled a blockchain-based payment system processing millions of dollars in deposits and withdrawals with 99.98% uptime accuracy across ETH, BTC, and LTC.
- Led the re-architecture from a static large bundle react application, SCSS, and providers to a scalable code split sever side rendered application in Next.JS, Zustand, and Chakra UI.
- Created the test suite infrastructure and automation to ensure code quality for our repositories to go from 0% code coverage to nearly 100% code coverage.
- Implemented data pipelines to properly surface data in Mixpanel to nontechnical team members to refine and improve our services and applications.

Senior Full-Stack Developer

2021 - 2022

Snapchat

- Led the architecture and design for Snapchat's Audience Insights tool that allows businesses to better target different audiences for their ads.
- Led design meetings, sprint planning, the general project timeline, and development steps to bring apps used by thousands of high-spending clients from idea to production.
- Adjusted pixel mapping in the Shopify ecosystem to allow stores to track user interaction from the Snapchat app better.
- Created a proper component design and versioning system that is leveraged by many teams throughout the company.

Senior Full-stack Developer

2019 - 2021

- Developed, maintained, and fixed bugs on dozens of websites, including being the project owner/lead developer for some of them.
- Oversaw the front-end development which included fixing bus and improving the existing mechanisms.
- Reworked the application's layout and appearance to add an improved, more modern feel and a smoother user experience.
- Communicated and discussed with the clients constantly, which included delivering project updates, providing assistance, answering questions, and receiving bug reports and feature requests.

• Developed various functionalities and pages of the application using Ionic and React, ensuring they worked properly on iOS and Android, and contributed to the application's web version.

Full-stack Software Developer

2018 - 2019

- Migrated the internal service application that all service centers run on to a custom in-house stack that used Node.js, Express.js, React, and Redux.
- Built a company-wide Node.js Express.js template coupled with Tesla OAuth that is now leveraged by all teams when spinning up a new application.
- Created complex user interactions and dashboards for metrics reporting and service center operation metrics.

Software Engineer Instructor

2016 - 2019

Starbucks

- Built a live KPI dashboard that scraped Starbucks' database of metrics daily and displayed changes in several KPIs to Starbucks' C-level executives.
- Created a live sentiment dashboard that streamed tweets regarding Starbucks, used NLP to break down their sentiment, and then averaged them daily to see how the public was reacting to Starbucks over time.
- Designed and developed various full-stack projects for internal teams, including but not limited to the projects above.

CORE SKILLS

- Libraries/APIs: React, Node.js, REST APIs, Redux-Saga, React Redux, JSON API, React Router, OpenAI API, Antd, Web3.js
- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Java, SQL, GraphQL, PHP, C#, Python, Less, SCSS, Python 3
- Frameworks: Redux, Express.js, Next.js, Jest, Vanilla JS, Bootstrap, Material UI, Cypress, OAuth 2, Tailwind CSS, .NET, Serverless Framework, JSON Web Tokens (JWT)
- **Platforms**: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Contentful, Docker, Klaviyo, Android, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Ethereum, Heroku, Blockchain, Amazon EC2, Vercel
- Storage: Amazon S3 (AWS S3), JSON, Databases, NoSQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Amazon DynamoDB, Redis
- Other: Cloud, Data Analysis, API Integration, Real-time Applications, WebRTC

EDUCATION

Silliman University Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

2014-2018

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: English (fluent)